how exciting is this we are going to be
studying the book of Revelation I know
this is the culmination of months maybe
even over a year how you wrong I think
so Oh daring to dream yes come on now we
talked about this actually originally
before all of us ended up sitting here
together we talked about this with a man
by the name of will Ferguson and will
was a personal friend of mine and of
Christ's he had a vision a dream he was
an evangelist a powerful speaker a man
of God and he had a vision in a dream
for the book of Revelation explaining
the book of Revelation with a very
strong emphasis on Christ and I believe
that will would have been here with us
of course I know he would have been with
us here today this is what he wanted but
actually accident took his life last
year and we want to dedicate this first
program - well yeah - sure and we know
he's resting in Christ yeah we know that
he's going to hear the voice of Christ
and that trumpet call in the morning and
he's going to be there he will not
precede him first Thessalonians chapter
4 well this program is going to be
pretty basic pretty simple we're going
to be opening up the book of Revelation
we're gonna be looking through the pages
the verses and trying to understand it
now I come from a background of studying
this book for some 30 years and yet not
really understanding it fully still and
I believe that's because the book is a
masterpiece it's it's a challenging book
and I think we're gonna be studying
through all eternity it's a summary of
the entire Bible in a way but it is a
book that's filled with symbolic
language it's a book that's filled with
mysterious representations of events and
history past-president future it's a
book that is difficult to understand a
book that's been blessed because God
wants to encourage us to us to study and
to understand it so I'm here at the
table with that background I want to
know a little bit about your backgrounds
in your relationship to the Jason
let's start with you well I'm relatively
new to the church coming back and
revelation is a book that's full of
symbols and signs and it's it's
confusing to me so I mean there's a lot
of it's kind of like a treasure map so
you're trying to figure out you know
what times what Kingdom does this symbol
represent where at least seven stars or
whatever seven candles do what are what
are all these things so I'm looking
forward to learning about Revelation
super yeah I guess I have read
revelation more than one time and I
still don't have the kind of grasp on it
that I want I feel like even though I've
read it even though I've read commentary
on it I still don't have that feeling of
you know that I really kind of know know
it and and I guess you know to kind of
reinforce what you were saying I guess
you never fully know it yeah but I could
have a better grasp on it so I think
that there are a lot of people who you
know who have read through it like like
I have but they just kind of still don't
really know so I'm looking forward to
this study because I really feel like
this is gonna open it up in a whole new
way amen
praise the Lord I do especially with the
Holy Spirit amen good deal so my
introduction to the book of Revelation
came when I was 12 years old 12 years
old when I was not a Christian okay I
had a cousin that had come over from
England and she began to talk to me
about the mark of the beast mm-hmm at 12
years old I'd seen this movie about this
little boy mm-hmm
who discovers he's the Antichrist and
anyone who finds out his arm he
identity dies a mysterious death Sosa's
they were telling me hey I know what the
mark of the beast is do you want to know
the mark of the beast is and I'm like oh
my goodness if I know what if I know
what the mark of the beast is I'm gonna
die oh you were taking that movie she
told me it was a there were so companies
that produced or so companies that had a
label on their boxes half circle o or
half a circle with a half moon and a
man's face in it she showed me the Box I
ran out the house screaming of
Revelation but and that kind of put a
taste in my after I didn't die I was
like okay man oh I think I want to know
more about this book and so it was years
later as it actually as a young adult
it's probably like 21 or 22 that I was
introduced to the book in a way that I
had I grown up really skeptic of the
Bible and someone introduced the book to
me I didn't know his background but he
was a well learned young man in the book
of Revelation and he began to like break
things down in a way that really caused
me to walk away from a contract that I
was in a music music career and it was
so powerful so amazing that I actually
walked away from this contract never to
look back so the book of Revelation has
become a you know one of the books that
for me is the most exciting book of the
Bible it just and I know there's a lot
of fear with people when they when they
come to that but like I was when I was
12 you know I don't want to know this
stuff because there's dragons and you
know things are gonna come up out of the
ocean and I don't want to be here when
that happened but understanding these
things represent symbols and signs of
greater realities and that there's not
to be like literal locust that looked
like you know men and you know those
kind of things once I got that
understanding the book became my
favorite book of the Bible mm-hmm mine
too yeah mine too I can totally relate
to that and that's why I think this is
going to be exciting because okay you
have that interest in the book of
Revelation you love the book of
Revelation now I have that same interest
in the desire Jason is a novice when it
comes to the book of Revelation he's
acknowledging hey I really don't get
this book I mean it's full signs and
symbols but I don't get it and Yvonne
has read it a few times and you've got a
grasp on it but yeah I'd like to know a
little bit better and I think you guys
are going to help moderate us and
together we're gonna be able to move
through this book in a way that should
open up more and more understanding
because I believe the Holy Spirit wants
to teach all of God's people and when we
get together even more so the Holy
Spirit wants to teach you you you and me
and now four times as much because all
four of us are together yeah and I
believe that this book is a book for the
end of time specifically and especially
now we're going to look at the book
we're gonna break it down just as it
overview just to kind of to make it into
more bite-sized pieces
sometimes when you when you come into
the book of Revelation like where do I
start you know and how do I get even a
grip on this well we're gonna break it
down into four basic sections with an
introduction and a close the
introduction is going to be Revelation
chapter one that's the introduction to
the book and I'm going to add to that
that's not me I think one of the things
that people look at when they get to the
book of Revelation is that they think
it's a book that's really just out of
order that there's no rhythm or rhyme -
yeah but when you understand that the
book of Revelation is I like to call it
divinely designed mm-hmm that's when you
begin to see oh there was meaning to
this and you can't just fit anything in
there it has to follow the pattern okay
so when I was on 19 a having had an
experience that I've never forgotten I
share this all the time I don't know
see those pictures that are just like
zigzag lines and well let me tell you
about I'm in the mall with my friends
and where I see all these people around
this picture and they're going oh look
at it so they call my interest I went
over there and it's just zigzag lines
and I'm looking at these people like you
are crazy no no you have to do this
thing with your eyes and as I do what
and they were like you gotta focus on a
particular so I'm trying to do all these
things with my eyes you know suddenly I
don't know if I focused in on one point
or what happened but that picture that
was just a zig zag zig zag lines
suddenly became 3d when I moved the
picture moved and I was like what so too
many people the book of Revelation yeah
exactly
oh I love it good I can't see anything I
mean where's the what are you getting so
excited about you know what are you
giving but when you see that there's a
pattern to the book and that's what
we'll be talking about in these you know
in this opening lesson when there's a
when you see the pattern to the book you
see that there is one behind that
pattern a divine designer and that
pattern really helps to make things come
alive come alive and like 3d so we'll be
covering those patterns and hopefully
that will bring it to life yes I love
that you know again I reminds me of when
I was first studying the book of
Revelation and I decided to rewrite it
in order I wanted to put all the second
comings in order and I wanted to put all
the judgments in order and I wanted to
put everything about Christ so that
because it wasn't written in or I don't
know who put this together
[Laughter]
I'm putting in this order but you know
it needed to be and since then I've
realized you know the more I've studied
the book of Revelation the more I've
realized how little I know so I don't
think any of us should should be
handicapped by the idea that hey we're
just not scholarly this book is just too
much for us this is too difficult it's
kind of like I for when he first looked
at that paintings like I'm liking
anything out of this man everyone else
is but I'm not sometimes we come to the
book of Revelation that way and we don't
need to to feel as though we're on the
outside all that guy knows all about
Revelation I'll just sit at his feet
I'll just learn what he know God wants
to actually communicate to us all of us
and show us what this book means now one
of the keys I think to understand the
book of Revelation is to break it down
into these sections and to allow Christ
to be the center that is something that
I know was on will Perkins heart pastor
Ferguson's heart and I know it's on iris
hearts on my heart when we look at the
book of Revelation sometimes we do think
about these gloomy pictures we think
about negative things Martin Luther
wrote an introduction to the book of
Revelation in the Year 1520 - and in
that introduction he said book of
Revelation doesn't really belong to the
Canon it shouldn't really be part of the
Bible Christ isn't there you know he's
not known in there he's not taught in
there but you know it was part so he
wrote this introduction talked about the
book of Revelation eight years later
Martin Luther changed his opinion eight
years later in his in his editing of the
introduction to revelation he said we
see now that Christ is both taught and
center of the book of Revelation and
that was I think a breaking point for
Luther that really was where his mind
now is able to grasp the prophecies of
Revelation because in a nutshell just in
a nutshell what revelation is doing it's
introducing us to Christ in the gospel
and then introducing us to that power
that influence that is symbolized by a
dragon that is going to counterfeit
Christ and the gospel that's that it's a
that's it in a nutshell
it's Christ and the
gospel here's the gospel his Christ
here's how it all works now be aware of
this dragon because he's actually come
down and he's trying to take from you
what Christ is giving to you and he's
trying to counterfeit everything that
Christ is established and we're going to
see that all true revelation we're gonna
see the truth counterfeit the truth
counterfeit the truth counterfeit that's
going in all the symbols I would say the
best way to understand really any
subject of the Bible is you know how can
I juice this down if you will to a level
that you know I could explain it in a
minute you know so just like what we
just heard okay really it's about Christ
and the dragon and then warring over the
people of God or over humanity you know
the the more ways you can sum it up for
your own self it's the better you you
begin to feel more comfortable
approaching the book because now you're
gonna be trying to trace that theme yes
all right right okay so Christ
dragon people where do I find that in
Revelation 1 revelation 2 revelation 3
going all the way through so the more
you can you can um you can find these
these patterns these parallels these
themes and then you now have something
you can trace through the whole book
instead of just jumping in and around in
reading revelation 11 where does this
fit what is it about you know without
the a theme or without the context right
yeah it's zigzag words but let's look at
that Jason would you read for us
Revelation chapter 1 and verse 5 sure
and we'll just pick this out here in
this verse and from Jesus Christ who is
the faithful witness and the first
begotten of the Dead and the Prince of
Kings of the kings of the truth of
excuse me of the kings of the earth unto
him that loved us and washed us from our
sins in his own blood now what I was
just saying applies to this verse what
we have here is we have a picture of
Christ and we have a picture of Satan
and we have a picture of us okay the
picture of Christ is a picture of love
and by the way it's really interesting
a few years ago there was a CNN blog
they have a religious blog on CNN and in
this blog it was March of 2012 they had
interviewed basically a a scholar a
biblical scholar and asked them about
the book of Revelation and this biblical
scholar said basically the book of
Revelation was forced into the Canon
kind of like what Martin Luther came up
with it was forced into the Canon
it doesn't really belong there we don't
even know if John was the author and we
don't know if the author read even the
Gospels and there's nowhere in the book
of Revelation that even says that Jesus
died for our sins the thing that got me
about that is that really brought home
to me is because because really
Revelation chapter 1 and verse 5 the the
verse that you just read Jason tells us
that Jesus Christ died for us loves us
and washed us from our sins that's the
gospel right there so when this scholar
interviewed on CNN said this I said wow
so much for scholarship so much for
scholarship in other words we don't need
to depend on the scholars when we open
up the book of Revelation in fact it
might be good not to depend on the
scholars and see that's a good really
good thing to think about because you
kind of ordinarily think I've got to
have somebody break it down for me you
know and and we're kind of doing that
here but yet we're asking the Holy
Spirit to to guide us and so in our
private study too we can ask the Holy
Spirit to guide us but this does I never
notice this before this verse has the
gospel it's it's John 3:16 I love the
idea of finding Christ in this book in
every nook and cranny that we can
because it it gives it a new meaning now
we're not just focusing on the dark side
rights all right but now we're focusing
on the love of Jesus and what he did and
how he's going to protect us in the end
and all of that so to me that's that's
that's awesome to find Jesus in every in
every nook and card
definitely important what you guys are
saying about learning that you have to
learn it for yourself because somebody
else might get it and get it wrong and
they're teaching you wrong you need to
learn for yourself what truth is amen no
no no and I'm gonna share this that the
the fact that the Bible I believe is
divinely designed is a way of actually
checking your conclusions mm-hmm because
just like a math problem you know you do
a math problem then you reverse the
problem to see if you got it right hmm
the Bible especially the book of
Revelation has those built-in mechanisms
where you can see am i right on this am
I wrong you know because as you it's got
to fit in the pattern okay I understand
the big picture the pattern you know
well I can't fit this in there because
that just throw the throws off the
entire yes pattern the entire design and
so all those things come into play but
what are you saying about this you know
the the gospel being in Revelation
chapter 1 verse 5 is is a beautiful
thought you know the first chapter you
have the gospel and we should be looking
for that theme all the way through
straight through because because an
introduction to any good book introduces
the theme of the book right so what is
the theme of the book well revelation
1:1
it's the revelation of Jesus Christ who
loved us and washed us from our sins in
his blood and here's the conflict you
were talking about the conflict we were
talking about the summary of the book
you have Jesus and you have the devil
and you have us where's the devil in
this in this verse who washed us from
our sins
what did sin come from well sin came
from the devil sin came from that
adversary who tempted Adam and Eve who
began the whole process of if you will
rebellion in the universe which by the
way is in a sense the the zenith of the
book of Revelation chapter 12 it gives
us a picture of this whole great
controversy and how it started in heaven
so revelation 1:5
also introduces in a sense to that dark
side to sin and guilt and shame and the
thing that led us to hide from God and
be afraid of God
and Jesus wants us to know right away
the first thing he wants us to know
right away in Revelation first message
of Revelation it's not about a beast
it's not about an antichrist not about a
dragon the first thing he wants us to
know I love you and I've watched you
I've taken care of the guilt I've taken
care of the sin I've taken care of the
very thing that was brought upon you by
venturing into that good and evil that
knowledge I didn't want you to have and
listening to the accusations the
insinuations of the Dragon which was the
serpent which is the devil I've cleansed
you from that I washed it from that I
accept you I believe in you you are mine
and this is the the picture we're having
here that is the I think is so
significant and beautiful yeah I want to
take you on a very quick just overview
of that very theme in the book of
Revelation mm-hmm and it was interesting
because as James and I were talking and
sharing some of these some of our
different thoughts before our program
and we're just like we've never really
studied the book of Revelation together
but we were amazed at how much we were
like whoa you're on the same page I was
seeing this in the very same way but one
of the things that we were sharing is
that the book of Revelation and this how
I'd like to put it is actually a love
story mmm
so when you put that for what revelation
a love story no it's not it's about
beasts and dragons but the book of
Revelation is about so are love stories
by the way what do you have you have the
Prince Jesus Christ you have his bride
of the church and you have this power
saying give me some time with your woman
and I bet you I can take her Wow that's
basically what he's saying
so the entire book of Revelation that
theme of Christ his bride and the dragon
saying I'm gonna steal her from you you
know so now revelation becomes a love
story and now just think of it when you
think of the book of Revelation within
that context we know that in Revelation
chapter one you have John who is who
Jesus says John
I want you to I'm calling you to do
something for me so John in essence we
can look at him as the friend of the
bridegroom okay
then in chapters 2 & 3 you have the
letters to the seven churches so what
are those those are Jesus's love letters
letters to his bride mm-hmm okay
in chapters four and five you have Jesus
standing before the Father but what is
he doing there he's standing there on
behalf of his bride right
chapter six deals with the seven with
the seals okay here you you see you see
the story of how Satan is trying to
corrupt the bride trying to lead her
away from her love Revelation chapter 7
you have the sealing of the people of
God so what is that sealing it's really
the perfecting of God's of Jesus's bride
revelation 8 through 11 are the trumpets
what is Jesus doing there in the
trumpets he's protecting his bride
throughout the ages right from the time
of the cross which we'll get into more
detail but this is just an overview
revelation 12 to 13 you have Satan
physically assaulting the bride going to
make war with the remnant of her seed
I'm gonna persecute you I'm going to
demonstrate that this woman doesn't love
you someone that means to something
called the mark of the beast and I bet
you that to save herself she'll receive
it those are the basic sections of
Revelation you've got the seven churches
the seven seals the seven trumpets
salute and in that last section which we
call the seven signs of salvation those
are four basic and all of those sections
repeat and enlarged they tell the same
story from a different angle it's very
similar to Daniel Daniel two seven eight
and eleven are four chapters that repeat
and enlarge on the same basic theme so
you've got an introduction in revelation
one and you've got a close in revelation
22 and then you've got these four basic
themes or stories that are told from
different angles covering the same
ground and giving more insight and more
understanding until we finally get to
this picture in Revelation 12 13 14 and
onward that I think primarily applies to
us today and future to us in other words
that our
just before us James the story ends
happily ever after to take his bride
yeah it was right at home after he saves
her saves the day you know those plagues
really the plates at the end of time are
really God's saying you're not gonna
touch my woman mm-hmm
Wow how dare you try to put a hand on
her ha ha the plagues are God's are
Christ saying no I'm protecting her he
comes to get the bride mm-hmm goes home
with her to our wedding
Wow happily ever after you know wow that
is so deep one author has said if a man
is really in love with a woman he'll do
the three P's he'll protect her he'll
provide for her and he'll profess her
and Jesus does all of that I like that
that wraps up the picture really well I
like that so so when we're looking at
the book of Revelation
Ivano let's go into the into the
sections yeah when we're looking at the
book of Revelation we're gonna be
looking at these these four sections
Revelation chapter 1 is what we call the
introduction of the prologue revelation
chapters 2 & 3 7 churches revelation
chapters four through eight one seven
seals Revelation chapter 8 verse 2 to 11
1970 after 12 all the way to 22 and
verse 5 is what we call the seven
salvation signs and we'll talk a little
bit about what we mean by that and in
Revelation chapter 22 6 all the way
through 22 21 that's going to be the
epilogue where the close that's going to
be the basic layout of the book of
Revelation that we're going to be
looking at as we move through it
step-by-step and in our next program we
just got a couple minutes left here time
is flown by but in our next program
we're gonna do an introduction and we're
just going to spend as much time as we
need in Revelation chapter 1 we've we've
kind of touched on it a little bit but
we're gonna we're gonna start in
Revelation chapter 1 now our goal for
this series this first series on Bible
prophecy our goal is to make it halfway
through the book however and I talked
we sat down we over the phone and we
went through a number of different
sessions together outlines and we
thought how far can we get in the first
session can we cover the whole book now
we can't covered there's no we're gonna
what about halfway through yeah let's
make that a goal so our goal is to get
through revelation 11:2 to make it to
revelation 12 verse 1 however we are not
cemented into that goal we don't have to
get that it's good we're just going to
move through if we only get to chapter 2
in the whole thirteen sessions that's
fine if we get further than that that's
fine too what we'd like to do is we
would like to make sure that you guys
you've on Jason that you are moderating
us we want to be able to move through
this book no faster than you guys can
comprehend it and we want to be able to
understand and explain it in a sense
that anyone that is just listening in on
our conversation about this book is
going to get it it's going to click so
great what do you guys think is that do
you think that's a good plan I think
that's great I like the idea of just not
being forced into a time line you know
we just get it as we go as the spirit
moves get it yeah because this is heavy
stuff yeah it is and yet looking at this
the illustrations that some of the
illustrations that I ever brought out
you know the love story illustration and
the illustration of Christ Danny for his
bride well you know the dragon looking
at these illustrations to me really is
going to help us to comprehend these
truths so I'm looking forward to the
adventure that we're going to write the
logs together
yeah it's God let's pray together this
for clothes yes I just want to thank you
for this opportunity for this program
for all you're doing and going to do and
pray that you'll continue to bless us
guide us lead us as we study the book of
Revelation we pray in Jesus name Amen
you